A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Cooperative Extension, 1862-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Records of the Virginia Cooperative Extension, 1862-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 26
19.52 Cubic Feet; 23 boxes
This collection contains the administrative records of the Virginia Cooperative Extension, including correspondence, reports, financial documents, slides, videos, and the records of Bob Swain. The collection also documents the VCE's role in Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission, Virginia Association of Extension Secretaries, and their work within rural communities.
Virginia Cooperative Extension Service
Virginia Cooperative Extension (1995-)
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Extension Division
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research, except for boxes 22 and 23 which are restricted for confidentiality and personally identifiable information.
Acquisition Information
The Records of the Virginia Cooperative Extension were transferred to Special Collections and University Archives in 2015 and 2016.
Appraisal
Duplicate budget books were removed from this collection and destroyed.
Adminsitrative History
A University-wide Extension Division was established on July 1, 1966, by the General Assembly. It combined the activities of the Cooperative Extension Service, General Extension Division, State Technical Services, and Continuing Education Center. However, extension work at the university can trace its roots to 1906 when an extension program was established in Virginia as a result of the farm demonstration work began by Dr. Seaman A. Knapp in Texas in 1903. Dr. John D. Eggleston, the superintendent of public instruction in Virginia at the time and later VPI president, invited Knapp to speak at a meeting in Richmond and that talk resulted in the beginning of the program in Virginia. When the Smith-Lever Act of 1914 was passed, authority for extension, or demonstration, work was transferred to Virginia Tech and it became known as the Agricultural Extension until 1966, when it became the Cooperative Extension Service before being absorbed into the overall Extension Division. In 1995, the Extension Division became the Virginia Cooperative Extension and Agricultural Experiment Station Division, often shortened to the Virginia Cooperative Extension (VCE).
Scope and Content
This collection contains the administrative records of the Virginia Cooperative Extension, including correspondence, reports, financial documents, slides, videos, and the records of Bob Swain.
The records are divided into eight seires. The first series, Rural Communities, contains videotapes from Rural Communities and notes. Series II, Reports and Statistics, includes statistical and narrative doruments, annual reports, plans of work, and progress reports.
The third series, Bob Swain records, are subdivided chronologically. This series includes budgets, financial statements and reports, allotment estimates, salaries, expenditures, legistlative documents, treasurer's statements, interest on federal funds, and extension donations.
Series four, Extension Administration Records, is restricted due to the contents containing perosnal information. The fifth series, JLARC, contains action reports, correspondence, news and media, recordings and other documents relating to the Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission from 1862 to 1993. Series six, Virginia Association of Extension Secretaries, contains correspondence, meeting notes, newsletters, and other documents from 1958-1993. The seventh series contains papers from the presentation Lucy is Still Here, and the last series, Slides, contain slides from New 4-H leader orientation and inflation.
Arrangement
The Records of the Virginia cooperative Extension are organized into the following series:
Series I. Rural Communities, 1993-1994
Series II. Reports and and Statistics, 1926-1949
Series III. Bob Swain Records, 1907-1990
Series IV. Extension Administration Records, 1994-1997
Series V. Joint Legistlative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC), 1962-1993
Series VI. Virginia Association of Extenison Secretaries, 1958-1993
Series VII. Lucy Is Still Here papers, 1980-1989
Series VIII. Slides, 1980-1989
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
Publications have been separated to the Rare Book Collection.
Additional audiovisual tapes and reels are available, and a separate inventory is online.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Agricultural extension work; University Archives; University History
Organizations:
Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Cooperative Extension (1995-); Virginia Cooperative Extension Service; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Extension Division
Contents List
- Series I. Rural Communities, 1993-1994
  - Rural Communities Videotapes
    - Rural Communities Class #1, 1994-01-28 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #2, 1994-01-25 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #3, 1994-02-01 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #4, 1994-02-08 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #5, 1994-02-15 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #6, 1994-02-22 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #7, 1994-03-01 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #8, 1994-03-08 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #9, 1994-03-15 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #10, 1994-03-22 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #11, 1994-03-29 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #12, 1994-04-05 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #13, 1994-04-12 (Box 1)
    - Rural Communities Class #14, 1994-04-19 (Box 2)
    - Rural Communities Class #15, 1994-04-25 (Box 2)
    - Rural Communities Class #16, 1994-05-03 (Box 2)
    - Rural Communities: Legacy and Change Tape 7 of 12 (Box 2)
    - Rural Communities: Legacy and Change Tape 12 of 12 (Box 2)
  - Video Notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Social and Economic Perspectives, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series II. Reports and Statistics, 1926-1949
  - Statistical and Narrative
    - Dec. 1940 - Nov. 1941, 1940-12-1941-11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dec. 1941 - Nov. 1942, 1941-12-1942-11 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dec. 1942 - Nov. 1943, 1942-12-1943-11 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Dec. 1944 - Nov. 1945, 1944-12-1945-11 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Dec. 1945 - Nov. 1946, 1945-12-1946-11 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Dec. 1946 - Nov. 1947, 1946-12-1947-11 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Dec. 1947 - Nov. 1948, 1947-12-1948-11 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Dec. 1948 - Nov. 1949, 1948-12-1949-11 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Dec. 1954 - May 1955, 1954-12-1955-05 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - June 1956 - Nov. 1956, 1956-06-1956-11 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Dec. 1956 - Nov. 1957, 1956-12-1957-11 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Dec. 1957 - Nov. 1958, 1957-12-1958-11 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Dec. 1958 - Nov. 1959, 1958-12-1959-11 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Dec. 1959 - Nov. 1960, 1959-12-1960-11 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Dec. 1960 - Nov. 1961, 1960-12-1961-11 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Jan. 1961- Dec. 1962, 1961-01-1962-12 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Jan. 1 - Dec. 31, 1963, 1963-01-01-1963-12-31 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Jan. 1 - Dec. 31, 1964, 1964-01-01-1964-12-31 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Jan. 1 - Dec. 31, 1965, 1965-01-01-1965-12-31 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Annual Reports
    - Annual Report 1926, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Annual Report 1927, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Annual Report 1928, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Annual Report 1929, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Annual Report 1930, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Annual Report 1931, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Annual Report 1932, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Annual Report 1933, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Annual Report 1934, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Annual Report 1935, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Annual Report 1936, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Annual Report 1937, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Annual Report 1938, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report 1939, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report 1940, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report 1941, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report 1942, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report 1943, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Annual Report 1944, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report 1945, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Annual Report 1946, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Annual Report 1947, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Annual Report 1948, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Annual Report 1949, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Annual Report 1950, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Annual Report 1951, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Annual Report 1952, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Annual Report 1953, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Annual Report 1954, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Annual Report 1955, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Annual Report 1956, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Annual Report 1957, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Annual Report 1958, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Annual Report 1958, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Annual Report 1959, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Annual Report 1959, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Annual Report 1960, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Annual Report 1961, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Annual Report 1962, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Annual Report 1963, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Annual Report 1964, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Annual Report 1965, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Annual Report 1966, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report 1967, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report 1968, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report 1969, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report 1/1970-6/1970, 1970-1-1970-6 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Plan of Work (POW), 1953-1964
    - Year 1952, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Year 1953, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Year 1954, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Year 1955 and Program Calendars, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Year 1957 and Program Calendars, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Year 1958 and Program Calendars, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Year 1959 and Program Calendars, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Year 1960 and Program Calendars, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Year 1961 and Program Calendars, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Fiscal Year 1962-1963, 1962-07-1963-06 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Year 1963 and Program Calendars, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Plan of Work, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Year 1964, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Year 1965, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Plan of Work 1967, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Extension Program Development Progress Reports
    - 1972 Progress Report, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - 1973 Progress Report, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - 1974 Progress Report, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Series III. Bob Swain Records, 1907-1990
  - Historical Financial Budgets, Records, and Reports, 1907-1929
    - Budgets
      - Budget, 1915-1916 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
      - Budget, 1916-1917 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Budget, 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Budget, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Budget, 1919-1920 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Budget, 1921-1922 (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
      - Budget, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Budget, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Budget, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Budget, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Budget, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
      - Budget, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Tentative Budget, 1926-1927 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Budget, 1926-1927 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Budget, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Budget, 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Budget, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Financial Statements and Reports
      - Financial Report, 1915-1916 (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Financial Report, 1916-1917 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Financial Report, 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Financial Report, 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Financial Report, 1920-1921 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Financial Report, 1921-1922 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Financial Report, 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Financial Report, 1923-1924 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Financial Report, 1924-1925 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Financial Report, 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Financial Report, 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Financial Report, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Financial Statement, 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Financial Statement, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Allotment Estimates
      - Allotment Estimate, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Salaries
      - Salaries Extension Workers, 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Salary Increases, 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Salary Increases, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - County Agents' Salaries, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Salary Increases, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Count Agents' Salaries, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Salary Schedule, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Expenditures
      - Expenditures (Quarterly Statement), 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Analysis of Expenditures, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Expenditures, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Expenditures, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Expenditures, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Legislative Documents
      - Smith-Lever Act
        - Hearings, Report, Debate: Smith-Lever Act of 1914 (Reproduction), 1959-10 (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
        - Smith-Lever and Smith-Hughes Memorandum of Understanding, 1917-1945 (Box 5, Folder 26)
        - Act and Amendments, 1920-1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Federal Legislation, Regulations, and Rulings, 1861-1917 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Record of Appropriations, 1907-1970 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Act Re County Appropriations, 1914-03-27 1931-03-21 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Funding of Extension Programs and Exhibits, 1914-1977 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Accounting Procedure, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Resignations, 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Publications, 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Quarterly Statements, 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Historical Financial Budgets, Records, and Reports, 1930-1944
    - Budgets
      - Budget, 1930-1931 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Budget, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
      - Budget, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
      - Budget, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Budget Estimates, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Budget, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Budget, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
      - Budget, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Budget, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Budget, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
      - Budget, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Budget, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Budget, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Budget, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Budget, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
      - Federal Budget, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
      - Budget, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Federal Budget, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Statements and Reports
      - Financial Statement, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Financial Statement, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Financial Statement, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Financial Statement, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Financial Statement, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Financial Statement, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Financial Statement, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Financial Statement, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Financial Statement, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Financial Statement, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Financial Statement, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - Financial Report, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Financial Statement, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Financial Statement, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Financial Report, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Allotment Estimates
      - Allotment Estimate, 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1933-1934 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Salaries
      - Salary Increases, 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Pension Statement, 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - County Agents' Salaries, 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Salary Increases, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Salaries, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Expenditures
      - Expenditures, 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Expenditures, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Office Expenditures, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Travel Expenses, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Interest on Federal Funds
      - Interest on Federal Funds, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Interest on Federal Funds, 1933-1934 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Interest on Federal Funds, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Treasurer's Statements
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1933-1934 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 35-36)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Treasurer's Report, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Number and Compensation of Employees, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Number and Compensation of Employees, 1933-1934 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Number and Compensation of Employees, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Finance, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Comptroller's Statement, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Report of State Auditor, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Anticipated Revenues and Proposed Salaries, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Historical Financial Budgets, Records, and Reports, 1945-1959
    - Statements and Reports
      - Treasurer's Statement, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - Financial Report, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      - Financial Report and Audit, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Financial Report and Audit, 1947-06-30 (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - Financial Statement, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Expenditure Statements, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Expenditure Statements, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Expenditure Statements, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
      - Financial Statement, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Financial Statement, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Financial Statement, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Report to State Council of Higher Education of Virginia, 1957-05 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Radio and Motion Picture File, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - AMA Project, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Federal Budgets
      - Federal Budget, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
      - Federal Budget, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Federal Budget, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
      - Federal Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
      - Federal Budget, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
      - Federal Budget, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
      - Federal Budget, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Federal Budget, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Federal Budget, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
    - Budgets
      - Budget, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
      - TVA Budget, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - TVA Budget, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Farm Labor Budget, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Budget, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
      - Budget, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Research and Marketing Budget, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Budget, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
      - Monthly Statement of Revenue (Budget Department), 1951 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Budget, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
      - Budget, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Budget, 1952-1954 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Monthly Statement of Revenue (Budget Department), 1952 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - TVA Budget, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Budget, 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - TVA Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - TVA Budget, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - TVA Budget, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Budget Exhibit, 1956-1958 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - TVA Budget, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - TVA Budget, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - TVA Budget, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Allotment Estimates
      - Allotment Estimate, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Allotment Estimate, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Allotment Statement, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Allotment Request, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Allotment Requests, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Donations - VPI Educational Foundation Soils Laboratory, 1959-1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Historical Financial Budgets, Records, and Reports, 1960-1974
    - Budgets
      - Federal Budget, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - TVA Budget, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Federal Budget, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - TVA Budget, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget, 1962-1964 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Federal Budget, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
      - Budget, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
      - Budget Exhibit, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget - Personnel Supplement, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget, 1964-1966 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Fiscal Budget, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Budget Exhibit, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Appropriations and Budgets, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Budget Exhibit, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Federal Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Summary of Budget Exhibit, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - F.E.S. Budget, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Budget Exhibit, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Federal Ext. Budget Information, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Budget, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Budget Exhibit, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)